-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案
The Case Book of Sherlock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第五季 第三集
S5E03
这是"王子"的马厩
And this is where the Prince is stabled.
啊 Robert爵士
Oh, Sir Robert.
很抱歉打扰你
Sorry to disturb you.
这是Joe Barnes
This is Joe Barnes.
Josiah的儿子
Josiah's boy.
我知道他是谁 Mason
I know who he is, Mason.
他在这儿干什么?
What's he doing here?
他对赛马很感兴趣
He's keen to race horses.
我会骑马 Robert爵士
I can ride, Sir Robert.
我想要做骑师
I'd love to be a jockey.
是吗?
Would you?
超过任何愿望
More than anything in the world.
嗯 很好 非常好
Well, that's good, very good.
但这跟我有什么关系?
But what has it got to do with me?
我想我可以为你工作
Well, I thought I could work for you.
我已经有足够的骑师了
I have all the jockeys I need.
请给我一次机会吧 先生
Please give me a chance, sir.
我可以清理马厩的垃圾
I'll muck out the stables,
清扫马场
clean the yard,
随您吩咐
anything you want.
我考虑一下
I'll think about it.
谢谢您 Robert爵士
Thank you, Sir Robert.
先生 您最好赶紧回屋一趟
Sir, at the house, you better come quick.
怎么了?
Why?
有麻烦了 先生
There's trouble, sir.
我告诉过你Beatrice夫人不舒服
I told you Lady Beatrice is unwell
不想被打扰
and does not wish to be disturbed.
我想我会成为她的特例
I think she'll make an exception in my case.
很抱歉 先生
I'm sorry, sir.
我接到严格的指示
I have strict instructions.
你是让我跟Beatrice夫人谈谈
Are you going to let me speak to Lady Beatrice
还是逼我使用暴力?
or will I have to use force?
你得先过我这关 Brewer
You'll answer to me first, Brewer.
这位先生坚持
This gentleman is most insistent
要与夫人谈话 先生
upon speaking to her ladyship, sir.
我警告过你永远不要到这儿来
I warned you never to come here.
我们的事可以在你的办公室谈 不是这里
Our business can be discussed at your office, not here.
我在很多场合试图解决这个问题
I've tried to settle this matter on many occasions.
你该知道的 Robert爵士
As you well know, Sir Robert.
想不到在New Market发生那事之后 你居然还有胆子来
You've got a nerve coming here after New Market.
这次我有把握
I'm leaving nothing to chance this time.
或许Beatrice夫人更乐于
Perhaps Lady Beatrice will be more prepared
听听理由
to listen to reason.
这是你我之间的恩怨 Brewer
Your grievance is with me, Brewer,
与他人无关
and with no one else.
这当然与Beatrice夫人有关系
It would certainly be of concern to Lady Beatrice.
Robert 这些人是谁?
Robert, who are these people?
他们要干什么?
And what do they want?
我来告诉你我要干什么 Beatrice夫人
I'll tell you what I want, Lady Beatrice.
请他出去
Get him out of here.
我要要回自己的东西!
I want what's rightfully mine.
出去
Get out.
滚! 趁你两条腿还能走
Go while you can still walk.
我会再来的 Beatrice夫人
I'll be back, Lady Beatrice.
再会
Good day to you.
很抱歉让你烦心 亲爱的
I'm sorry you've been upset, my dear.
他是什么意思 Robert?
What did he mean, Robert,
什么是本应属于他的?
what's rightfully his?
没什么可担心的
Nothing for you to worry about.
但我的确很担心 Robert
But I do worry, Robert.
我太了解你了
I know you too well.
他不会再来烦我们了
He won't bother us again.
如果他真的再来我们该怎么办 先生?
What should we do if he does come back, sir?
如果他再来
If he does come back,
我会亲自处理
I'll deal with him myself.
肖斯科姆别墅
Shoscombe Old Place
华生 你懂赛马吗?
Watson, do you know a bit of racing?
照理说应该懂一点
I ought to.
我的负伤抚恤金有一半都花在了这上面
I paid for it with about half my wound pension.
那我要把你当作我的"赛马指南"了
Then I'll give you my handy guide to the turf.
你的什么?
Your what?
你记得Robert Norberton这个名字吗?
Does the name Sir Robert Norberton recall anything?
小心
Careful.
他的马驹参加了冠军锦标赛
He's got a horse running in the Champion Stakes.
他住在Shoscombe庄园
He lives at Shoscombe Hall.
他的马厩在当地 被称为Shoscombe别墅
His stables are known locally as Shoscombe Old Place.
但你并不认识他本人?
But you don't know the man himself?
我从没见过他 如果你是这个意思
I never met him if that's what you mean.
他是出了名的危险人物
He has a reputation of being rather a dangerous man.
怎么个危险法?
How dangerous?
我记得数月前有一次
I remember an instance some months ago
他在New Market Heath用马鞭抽了一个人
when he horsewhipped a man on New Market Heath.
是Samuel Brewer Carson街的一位放债人
Samuel Brewer, the Carson Street moneylender.
为什么会发生这样的攻击事件?
What was the reason for this assault?
我猜是Robert爵士忌恨债主
Well, I imagine that Sir Robert had a grudge against moneylenders.
也就是说他负债累累
Or is heavily in their debt.
据说 他目前是日陷窘境
Well, by all accounts, he's so far down Queer Street,
可能再也不能恢复往日风光
he may never find his way back again.
我收到了John Mason的信
I received a letter from John Mason,
他是Shoscombe的首席训练师
the head trainer at Shoscombe.
信是一小时前寄到的
It arrived an hour ago.
亲爱的福尔摩斯先生
Dear Mr. Holmes,
您一定已经得知
you will no doubt have read
Samuel Brewer在几天前失踪的消息
of the disappearance a number of days ago of Samuel Brewer.
为了我的雇主Robert Norberton爵士的利益
In the interests of my employer, Sir Robert Norberton,
我想拜访您
I should like to visit you
来商谈一件十万火急的事件
to discuss a matter of the utmost urgency.
他不是约了时间嘛
He suggests a convenient time?
已经晚了几分钟
And already is several minutes late.
Samuel Brewer失踪了
Samuel Brewer's disappeared.
报纸已经大肆报道
The newspapers make a lot of it,
但我们还是先来说说Shoscombe吧
but let's hear more about Shoscombe.
Shoscombe犬
Well, the Shoscombe spaniels,
是Shoscombe别墅女主人的骄傲
special pride of the lady of Shoscombe Place.
她是Robert Norberton的妻子？
The wife of Sir Robert Norberton I presume.
不 不 他没结过婚
No, no, He never married.
他和他的姐姐 一位遗孀
He lives with his widowed sister,
Beatrice Folder夫人住在一起
Lady Beatrice Folder.
你是说 她寄住在他那里？
You mean she lives with him?
不 不 房子属于她的前夫 James爵士
No, no, the place belonged to her late husband, Sir James.
Shoscombe会出什么事呢?
What should be amiss at Shoscombe?
到底是怎么回事呢?
What indeed?
希望门外那位能够告诉我们
And here I expect is the man who can tell us.
请进
Yes?
我的蛋煮老了
My eggs were hard boiled.
有一位Mason先生想要见您 先生
There's a Mr. Mason to see you, sir.
谢谢 Hudson女士 请他进来
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson, show him in.
是 先生
Sir.
这边请
If you'll come this way.
-福尔摩斯先生 您收到我的信了吗? -是的
-You got my note, Mr. Holmes? -Yes.
但里面什么都没说
But it explained nothing.
要把细节都付诸文字
It was too delicate a thing
实在太难下手了
for me to put the details on paper.
事情太复杂了
It was too complicated.
你可以信任我的朋友兼同事  华生医生的谨言慎行
You may rely on the discretion of my friend and colleague, Dr. Watson.
-请坐 -谢谢
Please sit down. Thank you.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
我想Robert Norberton爵士是疯了
I think Sir Robert Norberton has gone mad.
拜托 这里是Baker街 不是Harley街 (伦敦著名的医疗街)
Please, this is Baker Street not Harley Street.
你为什么这么说?
Why do you say so?
我想是"Shoscombe王子"和冠军锦标赛
I believe Shoscombe Prince and the Champion Stakes
把他弄成这样的
have turned his brain.
-"Shoscombe王子"? - (马驹)
Shoscombe Prince?
华生 你真是无价之宝  一匹吗?
Watson, you're invaluable. A horse?
全英格兰最好的马 先生
The finest in England, sir.
事实上 Robert爵士必须赢得比赛
The truth is Sir Robert has got to win this race.
他已经无路可走 这是最后的机会了
He's up to his neck, and it's his last chance.
他把所有能够筹集的财产都押在了这匹马上
He's wagered everything he could raise or borrow on the horse,
他把所有欠款
and he's holding off his creditors
都拖延到大赛之后归还
till after the big race.
如果"王子"输掉了比赛 他就完蛋了
Oh, if the Prince fails him, he's done for.
你是猜测Robert爵士的债务
And you're assuming there's a connection between Sir Robert's debts
与Samuel Brewer的失踪之间有关联
and the disappearance of Samuel Brewer.
他是Robert爵士的主要债权人
He's Sir Robert's principal creditor,
而且我得指出
and I don't mind admitting
他们之间没有任何好感
there's no love lost between them.
在New Market的事情发生之后
Well, after what happened at New Market
我一点也不惊讶
I'm not surprised.
但那仅仅是开始
But that was just the start.
Brewer上周在庄园露面
Brewer showed his face at the hall last week,
Robert爵士像疯了一样朝他发飙
and Sir Robert flew at him like a man possessed.
说如果他再出现
Said he'd deal with him
他会亲自收拾他
if he ever showed his face there again.
我想他再也没回来
I presume he has not returned.
我不知道 先生
I don't know, sir.
不确定
Not for sure.
了解
I see.
如果财产危机真的发生
In the event of financial catastrophe,
Robert爵士有权主张他姐姐的地产吗?
would Sir Robert have any claim on his sister's estate?
据我所知不行
None at all as far as I know.
她只有非世袭的财产所有权
She only has a life interest in it.
在她死后 地产将归她丈夫的兄弟所有
It reverts to her husband's  brother after her death.
同时
In the meantime,
她能以夫人的身份收取年租
her ladyship draws the rents every year.
而钱都被她弟弟花掉了?
And her brother spends them?
差不多
That's about the size of it.
他的生活一定很坎坷
He must lead a most uneasy life?
或许吧 但他们一直是挚友
Well, maybe so, but they've  always been the best of friends.
他们志同道合
They have the same tastes.
她跟他一样热爱赛马
She loves the horses as much as he does.
至少曾经是
Or at least she did.
以前每天12点
Every day at about 12:00
她都要驱车去马厩看马
she'd ride down to the stables to see them.
尤其是
And above all,
她十分喜爱"王子"
she loved the Prince.
早上好 Beatrice
Good morning, Beatrice.
我等不及想看看当这个讨喜的小家伙
I can't wait to see their faces
第一个冲过终点柱的时候 他们会是什么表情
when this delightful creature is first past the post.
你怎么说 Mason?
What say you, Mason?
其它马不会有胜算 先生
The others won't stand a chance, sir.
赢它们三个身长 你说呢?
A three-length win, wouldn't you say?
三个半身长 至少
Three and a half, at least.
只是不要期望太高 Robert
Just beware of raising your hopes too high, Robert.
你不是唯一一个想让自己的赛马
You're not the only one who'd like to see
在冠军锦标赛上夺冠的人
his horse win the Champion Stakes.
但我是唯一一个拥有 "Shoscombe王子"的人
I'm the only one with a horse like Shoscombe Prince.
它的状态怎么这么好
Why he's on such good form,
你甚至可以亲自骑着它去夺冠 亲爱的
you could ride him to victory yourself, my dear.
我想不行了 Robert
I think not, Robert.
我们骑马的日子已经结束了
Our riding days are over.
你该休息的 亲爱的
You should be resting, my dear.
不 我很好 Robert
No, I'm fine, Robert.
真的 我很好
Really, I'm fine.
你知道医生的叮嘱
You know what the doctor said.
你比他还要大惊小怪
You fuss even more than he does.
Jasper 真乖
Jasper, good dog.
Carrie 你今天怎么样?
And how's Carrie today?
很好 谢谢 Robert爵士
Oh, very well, thank you, Sir Robert.
而在过去一周
But for the past week,
她的马车依然驶过马厩
her ladyship has driven past the stables
却再也没有来打过招呼
with never so much  as a good morning.
你认为他们之间有了争执吗?
Do you think there's been some sort of quarrel?
是彼此怀恨 来势汹汹  剑拔弩张的一次争吵
And a bitter, savage, spiteful quarrel at that.
现在 他都不会接近她
Now, he never goes near her.
她几乎都不离开房间
She hardly leaves her room
除了每天乘车出行
except to take her daily drive.
我想你亲眼目睹了这场争论的发生
And I assume that you have witnessed such a disagreement?
不 没有
Well, no, not exactly.
但否则为什么他要把她的宠物狗 送走呢 福尔摩斯先生?
But why else would he give away her pet spaniel, Mr. Holmes?
她喜欢那只狗 视如己出
She loved that dog as if it were her child.
你能给出任何理由为什么Robert爵士
Can you think of any reason why Sir Robert
要以这种方式令他的姐姐难过吗?
would wish to upset his sister in this fashion?
想不通
None at all.
这样对待一位心脏脆弱的女士实在太残忍了
It's a cruel way to treat a woman with a weak heart.
简直差劲透了
It's damn rotten.
我得说我并不认为他犯了什么罪
I must say he does not appear to be  committing any crime that I recognize.
那为什么Robert爵士要在夜里离开宅子?
So why did Sir Robert leave the house at the dead of night,
他去见的人是谁呢?
and who was the man he met?
说下去
Go on.
是管家Stephens看到他出了门
Well, it was Stephens, the butler, who saw him leave,
然后告诉了我
and he told me about it.
所以第二天夜里我们跟踪了他
So the next night we followed him.
那是谁
Who was it?
-Samuel Brewer? -当时太黑了 看不清他的脸
-Samuel Brewer? -It's too dark to see his face.
Robert爵士在什么时候送走了他姐姐的狗?
When did Sir Robert give away his sister's dog?
一周前的今天
A week ago today.
Jasper在磨坊里鬼哭狼嚎
Jasper was howling like a banshee at the mill house,
但身为主人也不该就这么送人呀
but that was no good reason for the master to do what he did.
Robert爵士
Sir Robert.
我要它离开这里
I want it offthis estate.
我不在乎你怎么处置它
I don't care what you do with it
只要别再让我看到它
just as long as I never have to see it again.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
我把狗给了Sandy Bain
I gave the dog to Sandy Bain,
一位骑师
the jockey.
好了 Jasper
Right then, Jasper.
我们去喝点东西吧
Let's you and I go for a drink, hey.
走吧
Come on.
第二天早上 他把狗给了Josiah Barnes
Next morning, he took it to Josiah Barnes,
Crendall那儿的Green Dragon旅馆的老板
the landlord at the Green Dragon in Crendall.
Beatrice夫人有贴身伴侣吗?
Does Lady Beatrice have a companion?
有个女仆 福尔摩斯先生
Her maid, Mr. Holmes.
只有一个?
Just the one?
Carrie Evans
Carrie Evans.
但她已经跟随夫人五年了
But she's been with her this five years.
那她很忠心了?
And is no doubt devoted?
她的确很忠心 不过我不能说是对谁
She is devoted enough, and I won't say to whom.
哦?
Uh-huh.
我不能搬弄是非
I can't tell tales out of school.
Robert爵士挺会讨女人欢心的吧?
Sir Robert is something of a lady's man, hey?
你不觉得姐弟间的不睦
Do you not think the quarrel
可能是由此产生的吗?
between brother and sister may lie there?
哦 这个流言早已是人尽皆知了
Oh, that scandal has been  pretty clear for a long time.
但Beatrice夫人或许之前没有发现
But Lady Beatrice may not have seen it before.
让我们假设她突然知晓了
Let us suppose that she suddenly found it out,
于是要辞退这个讨她厌的女仆
and she wants to be rid of the hated maid.
但他不同意
He will not permit it.
于是她拒绝跟他说话
She refuses to speak to him.
而Robert爵士一怒之下
And Sir Robert in his anger
送走了她的爱犬
gives away her dog.
不止这些 福尔摩斯先生
There's more to it than that, Mr. Holmes.
Mason先生
Mr. Mason,
你比我们有优势
you have the advantage of us.
可能还有些你
Perhaps there is something
没有告诉我们的事
that you have not told us.
地下室里有个中央暖气锅炉
There's a central heating furnace in the cellar.
已经许久未用了
It's been off for some time,
但Robert爵士抱怨天冷
but Sir Robert complained of cold.
又把它烧了起来
And had it on again.
Harvey负责烧锅炉
Harvey runs it.
他是我的一个伙计
He's one of my lads.
他感到不妙 福尔摩斯先生
He didn't like the look of it, Mr. Holmes.
昨晚把这个交个了我
And he brought it to me last night.
Harvey多久烧一次炉子?
How often does Harvey attend the furnace?
他每晚把炉子烧起来
He makes it up every evening,
然后就离开
and then he leaves it.
那么有人能在晚上出入那里吗?
So anyone can visit it during the night?
我想是的
I suppose so.
但伙计拿着大门的钥匙
But the lad has the key to the outer door.
知道了
I see.
你提到的那个旅店叫什么?
What is the name of that tavern you spoke of?
Green Dragon
Green Dragon.
在Parkshire有不错的钓鱼点吧?
Is there any good fishing in that part of Parkshire?
河沟里有鲑鱼
There's trout in the millstream
湖里有梭子鱼
and pike in the lake.
已经够好了
That's good enough.
你认为这是什么 华生?
What do you make of it, Watson?
这是大腿的上髁
It's the upper contour of a femur.
人骨吗?
Human?
毫无疑问
Without a doubt.
这是在唬人 先生
It's a bluff, sir.
可能是任何人寄来的
Anyone could have sent it.
也许是个马探子
It could be a tout.
我不在乎谁写的
I don't care who it is.
我要知道他所写的内容中 是否有属实的部分
I need to know if there's any truth in what he's written.
我离开的期间 Carrie负责照顾家中事务
Carrie will be in charge of the house while I'm away.
Carrie吗 先生?
Carrie, sir?
你得把心思放在"王子"的训练上
Your concern must be for the Prince's training.
没有再比那更重要的事了
Nothing is more important than that.
53...
Fifty-three,
54...
Fifty-four,
55...
Fifty-five.
有何吩咐 女士?
Yes, ma'am?
谢谢 Stephens 把餐盘拿走吧
Thank you, Stephens, please take the tray now.
56...
Fifty-six.
我黎明时出发
I leave at dawn.
两间房是吗 先生?
Two room,is that right, sir?
再要两杯你这儿最好的酒
And two glasses of your best ale.
好的 先生
Right, sir.
-福尔摩斯 -嗯?
Holmes? Hm?
嘘
Sh.
先生们 你们好
Good day, gentlemen?
你好 老家伙
Hello, old fellow.
哦 女士们 不好意思
Oh, ladies, I'm so sorry.
我刚才没注意你们坐在这
I didn't see you sitting there.
这里真是寒风凛冽啊 不是吗?
There's quite a bite in the air, isn't there?
你想要更自由些吧?
Oh, you'd much rather be free, wouldn't you?
老板!
Landlord!
难道一定要把这条狗栓得这么紧吗?
Is it really necessary to keep this dog tied up like this?
先生 如果不栓紧了
If I didn't, sir,
它一溜烟就会跑回原来的主人家
it'd be off back to the owner in a jiffy.
你看 先生 Jasper是只Shoscombe犬
You see, sir, Jasper's a Shoscombe spaniel.
哦 我本该看出来的
Oh, I should have known.
瞧 我也是个爱狗之人
You see, I'm quite a dog enthusiast myself.
等等
Wait.
拿行李时小心点
Be careful with that luggage
否则我活剥了你的皮
or I'll skin you alive.
请别放心里去 先生们
Don't you mind him, sirs.
他还要照顾他的母亲
He takes after his mother.
是出来钓鱼的吗?
Out for a bit of fishing, hey?
我们想在Hole湖
We thought we might try and land a pike or two
钓几条梭子鱼
at the Hole Lake.
没等你钓到鱼
You might find yourselves in the lake
你自己就先掉里头去了
before you were through.
为什么呢?
Why is that?
因为Robert爵士极度警惕
That Sir Robert is terrible jealous of anyone
怕有人监视他的马厩
who might be spying on his stables.
我们又不是马探子
Well, we're not touts.
他是那种先斩后奏的人
He's the sort that strikes first and speaks afterwards.
华生 我们午餐前
Watson, I think we should take a little walk
出去走走吧
before lunch.
主意不错
Well, that's a splendid idea.
老板 我们可以把狗带上吗?
Do you think we could take the dog with us, Landlord?
当然可以 先生们
By all means, gentlemen.
只是记得我说的关于Robert爵士的事
But mind what I said about Sir Robert.
走这边 华生
It's this way, Watson.
Robert爵士现在如何了?
What about Sir Robert?
据我估计
By my estimate,
他现在应该在去York的路上
he should be well on his way to York by now.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
因为我给他发了封电报
Because I had a telegram sent to him.
福尔摩斯 你有什么目的?
Holmes, what have you been up to?
当然 Palmer是最有希望获胜的
Of course, Palmer's the Favorite
就养在York附近的马厩里
is stabled somewhere near York.
我只是提示他那匹马
I merely advised him that the horse has shown
最近几天有了长足的进步
much improvement in the last few days.
当他发现自己被愚弄了可不会高兴的
He won't be pleased when he finds he's been duped.
我确定他会气急败坏
I'm sure he'll be furious.
Jasper
Jasper.
来啊 小伙 你好啊
Come on boy, hello boy.
你怎么样啊
How are you aye, hello.
Jasper 这儿
Jasper. Here.
我认识你们吗?
Do I know you?
不 但显然Jasper认识你
No, but evidently, Jasper knows you.
你一定是Sandy Bain
You must be Sandy Bain.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
是你上周把Jasper送到旅店的
It was you that brought Jasper to the tavern last week.
是的
That's right.
你喜欢动物吗?
You're fond of animals?
它们都由上帝所造 先生
They're all God's creatures, sir.
我不愿看到它们受伤害
I won't see no harm come to them.
Mason先生似乎认为
Mr. Mason seemed to think
Jasper幸运的逃脱了
that Jasper had a lucky escape.
他那么做
He must have had a reason
一定是有原因的
for behaving like he did.
我相信Robert爵士的确有他的动机
I'm sure Sir Robert had the best of motives.
不 我是说Jasper
No, I'm talking about Jasper.
他一直很安静
He's always such a quiet dog.
一定是发生了什么
Well, something must have happened to him.
在那磨坊里?
At the millhouse?
不 先生
No, sir.
地下室?
The cellar?
不 先生 是在老教堂里
No, sir, at the old church.
事情就发生在我把它送去
It was the same morning
Green Dragon旅店的那天早上
I brought him to the Green Dragon.
那是个破旧损毁的小礼拜堂
It's an old ruin chapel,
下面有个地下室
and under it there's a crypt
在本地声名并不好
which has a bad name among us.
Jasper
Jasper.
别过去
Not that way.
Jasper
Jasper.
Jasper 回来
Jasper, come back.
Jasper
Jasper.
来啊 孩子
Come on, boy.
来啊 我可不是在玩
Come on. I'm not playing games now.
Jasper
Jasper.
这里离庄园有多远?
How far are we away from the hall?
大约四分之一英里 先生
About a quarter of a mile, sir.
Beatrice夫人是在正午乘车出行吧?
I'm correct in thinking that  Lady Beatrice takes a drive about midday?
对 先生
Yes, sir.
谢谢 事不宜迟
Thank you, we've not a moment to lose.
快走 Jasper 快走 华生 快走
Come Jasper, come Watson, come.
拦住马车 华生
Stop the carriage, Watson,
拦住马车
stop the carriage!
不好意思
Excuse me.
请问去镇上的Green Dragon该怎么走?
Could you direct us to the Green Dragon in town?
快走 快走
Drive on, drive on.
呆着 别过来
Stay, stay back.
别过来
Stay back.
在Beatrice夫人明天再次乘车出行之前
Well, there's nothing we can do
我们没什么能做的
until Lady Beatrice takes her drive again tomorrow.
你还没解释为什么
You still haven't explained
今天午后要我那样冒险拦车
why I risked my life this afternoon.
为了验证一个推理
To test a theory.
你一定很失望
You must be very disappointed.
没验证成功却害我差点丧命
I was almost killed instead.
相反 我想我的小实验很成功
On the contrary, I think my little experiment was quite successful.
我怎么没看出来
I fail to see how.
那只狗 华生 狗
The dog, Watson, the dog.
没想到什么吗?
Did that suggest nothing to you?
Carrie Evans决意
Well, Carrie Evans is determined
要让狗和女主人不能相见
to keep the dog and her mistress apart so.
没有别的吗?
There is an alternative?
有啊
Yes,
Robert爵士把那个放债人
that Sir Robert has done away with
Samuel Brewer做掉了
the moneylender, Samuel Brewer.
别忘了
Don't forget.
别忘了发现的人骨
Don't forget the human bone that was found.
我没忘
I haven't forgotten.
对我来讲 显而易见
It's perfectly clear to me.
他们之前有过争执
They've crossed swords before.
很可能这次Robert爵士
It's possible that Sir Robert
做得太过分了
has gone too far this time,
犯了谋杀罪
and is guilty of murder.
那个孩子发现的
What the boy found
正是那位不幸的放债人的遗体
is all that remains of the unfortunate moneylender.
哦 不 不 谢谢你
Oh, no, no, thank you.
我饿死了
I'm famished.
新抓到的 福尔摩斯先生
A fresh catch, Mr. Holmes?
好久都没见到这么棒的了
Best I've seen in a long time.
真是"水深火热"啊 华生
These are deep waters, Watson.
水深火热 浊而不清
Deep and rather dirty.
我想借用地下室的钥匙
I would like to borrow the key to the cellar.
干什么用 福尔摩斯先生?
For what purpose, Mr. Holmes?
为了进门
To get inside.
Robert爵士在哪儿?
Where is Sir Robert?
Robert爵士昨天一早
Well, Sir Robert left for York
去York了
early yesterday morning.
今晚才能回来
He isn't expected back till some time tonight.
我本应带你四处看看
I'd show you around the house myself,
但主人走了 Carrie负责
but master left Carrie in charge,
她不会让任何人跨入大门一步的
and she won't let anyone past the door.
他指派一个女仆掌管庄园?
He left a maid in charge of the house?
我告诉过您 主人和夫人有过节
I told you things were bad between master and her ladyship.
Beatrice夫人的房间在哪儿?
Whereabouts is Lady Beatrice's room?
在一层 福尔摩斯先生
It's on the ground floor, Mr. Holmes,
因为她的心脏不好
on account of her ladyship's heart.
刚好在底层的...?
Precisely on the ground floor where?
走廊里第二间房
Second room in the corridor beside
在地下室入口旁边
the cellar passageway.
自从我们在Baker街的谈话之后
Has there been any change in the running of the house
房子里的人事有什么变化吗
since we spoke at Baker Street?
没想到有什么 除了我得解雇Harvey
None that I can think of, apart from the fact that
我的一个伙计
I had to dismiss Harvey, one of my stable lads.
他就那个在炉子里发现骨头的人?
Wasn't he the one that found the bone in the furnace?
是的
That's right.
为什么要解雇他?
What is the reason for his dismissal?
他偷了这里某个
Well, he'd stolen some money
雇员的钱 所以...
from somebody on the staff and so.
啊 这就是"王子" 福尔摩斯先生
Ah, here's the Prince himself, Mr. Holmes.
全身都闪耀着冠军的光芒 你说呢?
Every inch a champion, wouldn't you say?
是啊 非常出色的生灵
Yes, he's a very fine creature,
但你才是专家 华生
but you're the expert, Watson.
根本不是什么专家 福尔摩斯
Hardly an expert, Holmes.
我刚刚看到"王子"在
I am aware of the Prince's bursts of speed
最后一弗隆(英国长度单位)的爆发力 但问题是
over a final furlong but the fact is
它没有在大赛上赢过
he hasn't yet won a major race.
你是否依然认为它有很大胜算?
Do you think he's still in with a good chance?
如果它已经充分准备 那么是的
If he's given the ground, then yes.
好吧 好吧 等一下
All right, all right, hold your horses.
我来了 我来了
I'm coming, I'm coming.
下午好
Good afternoon.
你一定是Stephens
You must be Stephens.
是的 先生
That's right, sir.
我是位医生
I'm a doctor.
Robert爵士让我一有时间
Well, Sir Robert asked me to call on his sister
就来拜访他的姐姐
at the first opportunity.
我刚到此地
I'm new to the area.
他没跟我说过 先生
Well, he said nothing about it to me, sir.
他肯定是忘了
Well, he must have forgotten.
对于Robert爵士这样的大忙人来说一点不奇怪
Hardly surprising for a man as busy as Sir Robert.
恐怕夫人现在
I'm afraid her ladyship is out
在外面乘车兜风呢
taking her carriage exercise at the moment.
多长时间能回来呢?
How long is she likely to be?
不超过半小时 先生
Well, no more than half an hour, sir.
那这样的话 我不介意等着
Well, in that case I don't mind waiting.
看起来你也有病痛
You appear to be in some pain yourself.
是风湿病 先生
Well, it's the rheumatics, sir.
这把老骨头曾经
These old bones have taken a pounding
受过伤
in their time.
健康状况大不如前啦
Health's not what it was.
为什么不跟我说说呢?
Now, why don't you tell me about it?
您的意思是?
Beg pardon, sir?
既然我在这儿
Well, now that I'm here,
那不如看看我能帮上什么忙
I might as well make myself useful.
哦 你人真好 先生
Oh, that's very kind of you, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
是从我的手腕末端开始的
Well, it starts in the bottom of my wrist.
然后逐渐向上
And then it goes up.
到肩膀?
In your shoulder?
"S.B."
S.B.
当然 早晨一起床时
Of course, the worst time is
最难熬
first thing in the morning.
我的脖子和胳膊
My back and my legs,
哦 跟木板一样僵硬
oh, stiff as a board.
还有我的脚
And my feet,
我跟你说过我的脚吗?
did I tell you about my feet?
没有
No.
哦 我得跟你说说我的脚
Oh, I'll tell you about my feet.
冰块 就像冰块
Blocks of ice, like blocks of ice.
有时我都感觉不到脚的存在
Can't feel them sometimes.
你的血液循环不顺畅
Your blood's not circulating properly.
是个常见问题
It's a common problem.
还有另外一个问题
And then there's the other trouble.
另外一个问题?
The other trouble?
你知道的 另外一个问题
You know, the other trouble.
我试过各种方法
I've tried everything,
但都根本没什么起色
but it doesn't make any difference at all.
和以前一样痛苦
I'm in just as much agony now as I ever was.
袖子卷起来吧
Roll it right up.
哦 那是夫人
Oh, that'll be her ladyship.
她回来早了
She's back early.
很抱歉 不过恐怕
Please excuse me, but I'm afraid
我还有另一个紧急的门诊
I have another urgent appointment.
快到了 夫人
Almost there, my lady.
谢谢 Stephens 这就可以了
Thank you, Stephens, we'll be all right now.
谢谢 Stephens
Thank you, Stephens.
好吧 小姐
Right you are, Miss.
奇怪
Strange.
福尔摩斯 谢天谢地
Holmes, thank goodness.
幸亏卧室在底层
Fortunately, the bedroom is on the ground floor.
有什么新发现吗?
Did you have any luck?
一些事情还不明朗
A few things are still unclear,
但我希望
but before the night is out,
在天明之前解决
I hope to have solved the mystery
Shoscombe别墅的谜题
of Shoscombe Old Place.
假设Samuel Brewer再来庄园要钱
If Samuel Brewer returned to the hall to demand his money,
他可能会在晚上来
he might have done so at night.
可能就是Robert爵士
He could have been the man
在老教堂所见的人
that Sir Robert met at the old church.
可能Robert爵士大发雷霆
Perhaps Sir Robert flew into one of his rages
并杀了他
and killed him,
在惊慌失措中
and in a moment of sheer panic
把他丢进炉子
tried to dispose of the body
以处理尸体
by putting it into the furnace.
因此 这个钱包(出现在了那里)
Hence, the note case.
华生 别动!
Watson, the vibrations!
或许我得承认
If perhaps maybe I admit
我们现在掌握的都是间接证据
all the evidence we have so far is purely circumstantial.
哦
Oh.
松香
Resin.
松香?
Resin?
含有酒精成分
On an alcohol base.
这是在Beatrice夫人的房间里
Traces of it on a few strands of hair
找到的几根头发
found in Lady Beatrice's room.
来 华生
Come, Watson.
电报可不会让
The telegram will not
Robert在那儿呆很久
keep Sir Robert away much longer.
我们要去哪儿?
Where are we going?
Robert爵士
Sir Robert.
我不在的时候发生了什么事?
What happened while I was away?
没什么事 先生
Nothing, sir.
别骗我 Mason
Don't lie to me, Mason.
有人在背着我干一些事
Something's been going on behind my back.
是不是有人在这附近盘问?
Has anyone been around here asking questions?
没有人 先生
No one, sir.
但我在Crendall附近遇到一些人
Apart from some people I met near Crendall.
我不知道他们的名字
I don't know their names.
你们说了些什么?
What did you talk about?
没什么
Nothing much.
他们对老教堂很感兴趣
They were interested in the old church.
笨蛋!
Fool!
如果Samuel Brewer不是受害者
Well, if Samuel Brewer was not the victim,
那为什么他的钱包
why was his note case found
会在庄园的地下室里找到呢?
in the cellar of the hall?
这里还有谁的名字是以S.B.开头的?
Who else in the household has the initials S. B?
S.B.... S.B.
S.B., S.B.
Sandy Bain
Sandy Bain.
Harvey因为偷了别人的钱
Harvey was dismissed
而被逐出了房子
for stealing from other members of the household.
他的职责之一
One of his duties
就是照看地下室的炉子
was to tend to the furnace in the cellar.
事实上的确有尸体被烧了
Well, the fact remains that the body was burned.
如果那不是Brewer
If it wasn't Brewer's,
又会是谁?
then whose was it?
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
在这样一个地方
What could you possibly be able to find
能找到什么呢?
in a place like this?
铅衬被切掉了
The lead lining's been cut.
不出我所料
Just as I thought.
螺钉松了
The bolts have been loosened.
华生 我需要你帮忙把这个打开
Watson, I'm going to need your help to open this.
福尔摩斯 这是亵渎神明啊
Holmes, that's desecration.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你动我的东西干什么?
What are you doing on my property?
听见没有?
Do you hear?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你在这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
哦
Oh.
啊 福尔摩斯先生
Ah, Mr. Holmes,
发生了什么事?
what's happened?
问得好 Mason先生
A good question, Mr. Mason.
问题直指Robert爵士
One that should be directed at Sir Robert.
啊 该死的装置
Oh, blasted contraptions.
你怎么敢? 出去
How dare you? Get out.
我本想跟你们一起喝茶的
I was going to join you for tea,
但我好像来晚了
but I see I'm too late.
马上出去 否则我就叫Robert爵士了
Get out this instant or I'll call for Sir Robert.
Robert爵士知道我在这儿
Sir Robert knows that I'm here.
Evans小姐 请坐下好吗?
Please, Miss Evans, will you sit down?
我想如果不来向Beatrice致敬
I felt I couldn't visit Shoscombe Old Place
我就不能拜访Shoscombe别墅
without paying my respects to Lady Beatrice.
哦 你们喝茶的时候还喝白兰地
Oh, you have brandy with your tea?
当然是用来治疗的
For medicinal purposes, of course.
但这是不是足以让我好奇?
But is it enough I wonder?
好奇什么?
Enough for what?
白兰地是用来恢复精神的
Brandy revives the spirits.
我不认为这足够
I hardly think it is sufficient
用来唤醒死人
to raise the dead.
别动 Evans小姐
Don't move, Miss. Evans.
这样你就好受多了
That should be comfortable enough
等你自己的医生来吧
until your own doctor arrives.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是夏洛克 福尔摩斯
I am Sherlock Holmes.
或许你对我的名字很熟悉
Perhaps my name is familiar to you.
或许表面看来并非如此
I know appearances are against me,
但你必须相信
but you must believe that
我别无选择
I could act in no other way.
我很高兴你这样说
I'm very happy to hear you say so.
但我恐怕你得跟
But I fear your explanations
警察解释这些了
must be for the police.
求你了 Robert爵士
Please, Sir Robert.
这些行为的一切责任都由我一人承担
The responsibility for what has  been done is entirely mine.
Evans小姐和Joe Barnes
Ms. Evans and Joe Barnes
只是听从我的指示
were merely following my instructions.
你必须保证他们不受伤害
You must promise that they will come to no harm.
我无法跟你保证任何事
I can promise you nothing.
但我愿意听一听事情的真相
But I will hear a plain statement of the facts.
很好
Very well.
显然你对我的事情
You've clearly gone pretty deeply
已经了如指掌
into my affairs,
否则我不会在那儿碰到你
otherwise I should not have found you where I did.
我始终清楚如果Beatrice去世
I've always known that if Beatrice died,
地产将归由
the estate would revert
我姐夫的家人所有
to my brother-in-law's family.
所有东西都会被查封
Everything would be seized,
包括我的马厩和马匹
including the stables and the horses.
福尔摩斯先生
Well, Mr. Holmes,
我姐姐一周前
my sister did die,
的确去世了
just a week ago.
而你没告诉任何人?
And you told no one?
我没有多少选择余地
I had little alternative.
如果我公之于众 我将面对全面的破产
If I told the truth, I faced absolute ruin.
如果我延迟到比赛之后公开
But if I could stave things off until the race,
我知道一切都会好转
I knew all might be well.
Beatrice死于长期困扰她的
Beatrice died of the heart condition
心脏问题
that had long afflicted her.
这一点要由验尸官来确认
That will be for a coroner to decide.
她的医生可以证明
Her own doctor would certify that for months,
数月以来她的症状预示了这个结局
her symptoms had threatened such an end.
Joe Barnes在Beatrice去世前一两天
Joe Barnes came to see me in search of work
到我这里找工作
a day or two before Beatrice died.
他看起来是个值得信赖的孩子
He seemed a trustworthy lad,
所以我想到让他来
and it came into my mind that he might
假扮我亲爱的姐姐
for a short time
一段时间
impersonate my dear sister.
只要"她"每天出现在马车上
It was but a case of appearing daily in her carriage
因为没人会进她的房间
for no one need enter her room
除了Evans小姐
save Miss. Evans.
当然 我很信任她
Of course, I had to take her into my confidence.
整个骗局让我也很痛苦
The whole deception distressed me greatly,
但想不到其他办法
but I could see no other course to take.
很自然
Naturally,
尸体不能存放在卧室里
the body couldn't remain in the bedroom.
第一天晚上
On the first night,
Joe和我把尸体抬出来
Joe and I carried it out
放到老磨坊里
to the old mill house.
她的宠物狗跟着我们
We were followed by her pet spaniel
并且之后它一直在门口狂吠
which afterwards howled continually at the door.
所以我觉得应该找个更安全的地方
So I felt some safer place was needed.
我赶走了狗
I got rid of the dog,
我们把Beatrice
and we carried Beatrice
抬到教堂的地下室
to the crypt of the church.
我认为我们把她放在她丈夫的
It seemed to me to be no unworthy resting place
一位先人的棺材中作为其安息之所
if we put her for a time in the coffin
并没有什么不妥
of one of her husband's ancestors
她仍身处神圣之地
lying in what is still consecrated ground.
我每天都去向她致意
I paid my respects to her there every day.
至于我们从棺材中
As to the old relics
取出的遗体
which we took from the coffin,
Joe和我把它移走了
Joe and I removed them.
他晚上走出卧室并下楼
He descended from the bedroom at night
在炉子里焚烧遗体
and burned them in the furnace.
设计这么的复杂的诡计真的有必要吗?
Was it necessarily to lay that monstrous trap?
我认为没人
I was determined that no one
可以打扰我姐姐安息
should disturb my sister's rest.
但你是怎么开始怀疑她的死的
But how you suspected her death
我想不到
I cannot imagine.
是这样 昨天
Well, yesterday,
当Evans小姐命令马车夫开走时
when Miss. Evans ordered the carriage to drive on,
我推断她是在害怕什么
I concluded that she was afraid of something.
我怀疑她怕的正是Jasper
I suspected that something was Jasper.
Evans小姐知道狗不会出错
Miss. Evans knew that dogs do not make mistakes.
它会认出那不是它的女主人
He would have known that it wasn't his mistress.
但我们必须把此事交由警察
But we must leave all this for the police.
为什么?
But why?
我只需要一两天
A day or two is all I need.
求你保持沉默吧
Say nothing yet I beg of you.
只要比赛开始
The race will have been run,
我的噩梦就将结束
and my nightmare might be over.
我全身心地爱着Beatrice
I loved Beatrice with all my heart,
其中没有任何污辱或不敬
and there was no indignity or irreverence.
我不觉得我污辱了死者
I don't feel I have wronged the dead.
我知道我的动机很自私
I realize that my motives were selfish,
但我姐姐是不会希望
but my sister would not have wished
看到我破产的
to see me destroyed.
但这并不意味着你有权违反法律
That does not entitle you to break the law.
听听这个 福尔摩斯
Listen to this, Holmes.
在"Shoscombe王子"昨日夺得
Following the success of Shoscombe Prince
冠军锦标赛的冠军之后
in yesterday's Champion Stakes,
Robert爵士得到了足够丰厚的奖金
Sir Robert has received sufficient winnings
偿还了所有债务
to settle all his debts
并足够他重新过上
with enough left to reestablish him
优越的生活
in a fair position in life.
啊
Ah.
然而 Robert爵士姐姐的
However, the victory was marred
突然去世
by the sudden death
冲淡了胜利的喜悦
of Sir Robert's sister,
Beatrice Folder夫人
Lady Beatrice Folder
至少与他一样
whose love of horses
热爱赛马
was at least as great as his own.
甚至是避难在外的Samuel Brewer
Even the elusive Samuel Brewer
也从其法国的避难所归来
has returned from his hideaway in France
并发电报祝贺
to send a telegram of congratulations
Robert爵士的胜利
to Sir Robert on his win.
这表明债权人
It transpires that even creditors
也还有自己的债权人啊
have their creditors.
这解释了为什么Samuel Brewer
It explains why Samuel Brewer
那么急于要回自己的钱财
was so anxious to get his money back.
但发电报
But to send a telegram,
真是赤裸裸的伪善
such a bare faced hypocrisy.
那你靠"Shoscombe王子"赢了多少钱?
So how much did you win on Shoscombe Prince?
20吉尼(英国旧金币)
Twenty guineas.
真可耻
That's disgraceful.
香槟 Hudson太太?
Champagne, Mrs. Hudson?
当然了 正合时宜啊
Of course, in the circumstances.
哦 你真好
Well, that's very good of you,
但我只赢了20吉尼啊
but I've only won 20 guineas.
再加上我的10吉尼
Plus my ten.
你可不是唯一一个欲罢不能
You're not the only one that likes a plunge
一次次去赌马的家伙 医生
on the horses from time to time, Doctor.
哦 哈!
Oh, gee.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com